<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Hugo Apéro</title>
    <link>https://sayalaruano.github.io/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Hugo Apéro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sayalaruano.github.io/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The molecular basis of JAZ-MYC coupling, a protein-protein interface essential for plant response to stressors</title>
      <link>https://sayalaruano.github.io/talk/br_scs_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sayalaruano.github.io/talk/br_scs_2021/</guid>
      <description>This presentation was awarded as the best oral presentation of the symposium.
In this section you can find more details about this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corn Disease Detector</title>
      <link>https://sayalaruano.github.io/project/corndiseasedetector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sayalaruano.github.io/project/corndiseasedetector/</guid>
      <description>This project was built as a final group assignment during the Saturdays AI Quito 2021 artificial intelligence workshop.
Figure 1.- Logo of the Corn Disease Detector project. Retrieved from https://corndiseasedetector.github.io/.
Background     Infectious diseases are a major threat for many crops of high importance for the food security of many regions of the world. Each year, around 60% of farmers in Ecuador have reported pre-harvest losses due to infectious agents such as fungi and bacteria, in crops like banana, cacao, and potato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drug discovery project to classify ligands that bind to Beta-Lactamases</title>
      <link>https://sayalaruano.github.io/project/betalactamase_drug_discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sayalaruano.github.io/project/betalactamase_drug_discovery/</guid>
      <description>I developed this project as the Midterm assignment for the Machine Learning Zoomcamp. Data Professor proposed the idea and dataset of this initiative, a collaborative Open Bioinformatics Research Project that is still in progress.
Figure 1.- 3D-structure of a betalactamase (PDB ID: 2q9n). Retrieved from https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:PDB_2q9n_EBI.png. Used under a CC0 licence.
Background     This project aims to evaluate the activity of molecules that have been experimentally tested to bind or not bind to Beta-Lactamases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis of Ecuadorian political tweets from 2021 elections</title>
      <link>https://sayalaruano.github.io/project/ecuadorian_elections_2021_sentiment_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sayalaruano.github.io/project/ecuadorian_elections_2021_sentiment_analysis/</guid>
      <description>This project was developed as a final group assignment during the Artificial Intelligence course at my bachelor, which I took as requirement for obtaining of my minor in Systems Engineering.
Figure 1.- Natural Language Processing illustration. Retrieved from https://thenounproject.com/term/natural-language-processing/3261011/. Used under a CC-BY 4.0 licence.
Summary     In this project, we captured sentiments of replies to tweets from two Ecuadorian presidential candidates in the 2021 elections (@LassoGuillermo and @ecuarauz).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The molecular basis of JAZ-MYC coupling, a key component of plant immunity</title>
      <link>https://sayalaruano.github.io/project/jaz-myc_coupling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sayalaruano.github.io/project/jaz-myc_coupling/</guid>
      <description>I worked on this project during my bachelor, collaborating as undergraduate researcher at the Computational and Theoretical Chemistry Group - Universidad San Francisco de Quito, in Ecuador.
Summary     The jasmonic acid (JA) signaling pathway is one of the primary mechanisms that allow plants to respond to a variety of biotic and abiotic stressors. Within this pathway, the JAZ repressor proteins and the basic helix-loop-helix (bHLH) transcription factor MYC3 play a critical role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling of protein-protein interaction and search for key residues by machine learning of the JAZ-MYC3 complex of Arabidopsis thaliana</title>
      <link>https://sayalaruano.github.io/talk/rsg_argentine_sajib_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sayalaruano.github.io/talk/rsg_argentine_sajib_2020/</guid>
      <description>In this section you can find more details about this project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling of Protein-protein interaction and search for key residues by machine learning of a protein complex in the jasmonic acid route in Arabidopsis      thaliana</title>
      <link>https://sayalaruano.github.io/talk/-xliii_national_biology_conference_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sayalaruano.github.io/talk/-xliii_national_biology_conference_2019/</guid>
      <description>In this section you can find more details about this project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
